Guide to the Samuel Halperin collection, 1683-2007 MS2236
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Cartographic catalogues, MS2236 Series 3; 7.5 Linear feet
  - Martayan Lan, miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Martinus Nijhoff Antiquarian Bookdealers (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - McBlain Books (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Nicholas Morrell (Rare Books), Ltd. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Orbis Terrarum Antique Maps and Prints (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Overlee Farm Books (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Paul Roberts Stoney Print and Mapseller (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Quinto Bookshops, no. 36, 45, 46 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Regent Gallery ABA (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc. no. 9-12 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc. no. 13-18 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc. no. 20-23 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc. no. 24-25 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc. no. 26-27 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc. no. 28-29 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 30-31, 33-34 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 35-39 and special issue (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 40, 42-45 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 46-49 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 50 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 51-52, 54 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 55-57 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 58-59 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 60-61 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 62-63 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 64-65 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., no. 66-67 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Richard B. Arkway, Inc., Bulletins, no. 1-5, 7 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Robert Douwema (Prints and Maps), Ltd. no. 18-20 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Robert Douwema (Prints and Maps), Ltd. no. 21-23 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Robert Douwema (Prints and Maps), Ltd. no. 24-25 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Robert Douwema (Prints and Maps), Ltd. no. 27-28 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Robert Frew, Ltd., no. 8-9 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Robert Frew, Ltd., no. 13 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Robin Greer, no. 32, 36 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Rosenkilde and Bagger, Ltd. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Spaculum Orbis Terrarum Antique Maps and Prints (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sarum Original Antique Maps, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Sotheby's, 1939-1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Sotheby's, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Sotheby's, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Stanley Gibbons Antiquarian, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Stephanie Hoppen, Ltd. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Swann Galleries, Inc., 1972-1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Swann Galleries, Inc., 1981-1983 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Swann Galleries, Inc., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Swann Galleries, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Tejas Galleries, no. 15-17 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Suarez (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Tooley Adams and Co. Ltd., no. 1 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Tooley Adams and Co. Ltd., no. 2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Tooley Adams and Co. Ltd., 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Tooley Adams and Co. Ltd., 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Tooley Adams and Co. Ltd., 2000 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Tooley Adams and Co. Ltd. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - W. Graham Arader III, no. 9-14, circa 1976 - circa 1977 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - W. Graham Arader III, no. 15-16, 12/1977-06/1978 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - W. Graham Arader III, no. 19-19, 09/1978-08/1979 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - W. Graham Arader III, no. 20-26, 12/1979-11/1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - W. Graham Arader III, no. 27-30, 12/1980-07/1981 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - W. Graham Arader III, no. 31, 33, 55, 91, 1981-1992 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Waverly Auctions, 1981-1996 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - W.J. Faupel (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Walter Reuben, Inc., Rare Maps book, no. 30-35 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Walter Reuben, Inc. no. 34-36 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Walter Reuben, Inc. no. 38-39 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Windsor Collection (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Worldwide Antiquarian, no. 58, 61 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - International Directory of Map Dealers (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - World Directory of Dealers in Antiquarian Maps (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Cartographic collection resources, Circa 1936 - 1982; MS2236 Series 4
  This series, entitled "Cartographic collection resources," has materials that include brochures, tourist maps, and guides to collectors. Most of the documents are undated. The series is comprised of brochures and buying guides for cartographic collectors. There are also a few pamphlets containing articles dealing with matters in this field, tourist maps for visitors to the Holy Land, and guides for visitors to the Holy Land, primarily dealing with the collection and study of antique maps.
  - Brochures, buying guides (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Tourist maps - Holy Land (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Tourist guides - Holy Land (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Materials related to maps of Israel (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Maps of Israel, 1967, undated; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Survey of Israel road map [shows armistice lines and demilitarized zones], 1953; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Maps of Israel, 1941-1982; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Maps of Israel, Circa 1967-1973; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Maps of Palestine, Undated; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Peel Royal Commission on Partition of Palestine [19 maps], 1936-1938; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Magazines and posters, 1977-1999; MS2236 Series 5; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series, entitled "Magazines and posters," has issues of the periodical Map Collector. Issues range from the magazine's debut in 1977 until 1993. There is also one issue of Mercator's World, a similar publication, from September/October 1999. This periodical focuses on the world of map collecting, featuring articles, buying guides, and other useful information for collectors. There are also three posters for Washington, D.C. historical organizations.
  - Map Collector, 12/1977-03/1978 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Map Collector, 09/1978-09/1979 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Map Collector, 12/1979-09/1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Map Collector, 12/1980-09/1981 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Map Collector, 12/1981-12/1982 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Map Collector, 03/1983-03/1984 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Map Collector, 06/1984-06/1985 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Map Collector, 09/1985-06/1986 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Map Collector, 09/1986-03/1987 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Map Collector, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Map Collector, 09/1990-12/1991 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Map Collector, 09/1992-12/1999 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Posters (Tube 23, Folder 1)
  - Jerusalem From the Mount of Olives, circa 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Antisemitica, 1946-1970; MS 2236 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 29)
  This series contains has various pamphlets, articles, and other forms of propaganda of an Anti-semitic nature, created between 1946 and 1970.